

# **ROMAN KHOMETS** FRONT-END DEVELOPER (REACT)

# PERSONAL SUMMARY

Hi, I'm a quality focused frontend developer with experience in creating web apps using React/Redux/Rest API stack. Pay extreme attention to detail and have a passion for delivering a great user experience, provide strong critical analysis and problem solving. And it's not just a boilerplate, I really like the things I do and want to be proud of them. An eternal student, live to learn and it's never enough!

### CONTACTS



Petrikov, Belarus



+375 33 675 53 96









## **SKILLS**

React, Next Redux/Redux Toolkit Javascript/Typescript Node, Express, Nest MongoDB, PostgresQL Rest API (Axios) RHF, Formik Jest Git

SASS, Responsive Layout Material UI, Ant Design Photoshop

#### **LANGUAGES**

English (A2+/B1) Russian/Belarusian (Native)

# WORK EXPERIENCE

April 2022 - current

**Fullstack Developer at Uniblog** 

- Designed initial project structure, implemented key features
- · Participated in discussions about app functionality and its realization
- · Managed 5 person team of developers, created and allocated tasks among them, organized onboarding and support

August 2021 - February 2022 Freelance Frontend Developer

- · Created UI and logic for authorization, notifications, product pages etc
- Improved apps performance, layout design and UX
- · Fixed and enhanced existing features according to projects requirements

2019 - December 2021

**Individual Entrepreneur (Construction Service)** 

- · Developed and implemented strategic business plan in a highly competitive market environment
- · Fostering relationships to maintain existing clients, while developing new relationships to attract potential clients
- Designed and implemented marketing campaigns, resulting in ~30% orders increase

2017 - 2019

**Installation Crew Chief** 

- · Managed 3 person team of installers
- · Guided efforts to improve technological process in a real and cost effective way, resulting in saving of the worktime for about a half of an hour per day
- Trained new employees

#### **EDUCATION**

2021 - current

Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics **Engineer of Information Technology and Control** 

2021

**IT-Incubator** Frontend Developer

2017 - 2021

**Bobruisk State College of Forestry Forestry Technician** 

#### **ACTIVITIES**

DIY amateur Car travel

The care of homeless animals